我们几个月前就该这么做了
We should have done this months ago.
我去跑个步
I'm gonna go for a run.
好  先来确认一下安不安全
Okay. Let's just make sure it's safe.
-好  -可以  就是现在  快跑
- Okay. - Okay, now! Go now!
四天前
Four days ago,
我与克莱尔搬到了汽车道上来
Claire and I moved out here to the driveway.
当艾丽克斯也搬回来后
The house exceeded maximum capacity
家里人满为患了
when Alex moved back home.
她离开洋气的工作
She quit her fancy job
去做了低薪但道德高尚的工作
for something low-paying and ethical!
好棒棒
Yay.
有她  卢克  迪兰  海莉还有俩双胞胎
Between her, Luke, Dylan, Haley, and the twins,
家里退化回了混乱时代
things have devolved into total chaos.
艾丽克斯  开门
Alex! Open up!
我头发都快干了  我还没抹发蜡呢
My hair is drying, and I haven't put any product in yet.
去用老爸的
Go use Dad's!
我就不能有一点独处的时间吗
Ugh! Can I get like two minutes to myself?!
要亲命了
Oh, my God!
白痴  你吵醒宝宝们啦
You woke up the babies, you idiot!
这下可好  他也醒了
Great, now he's up.
靠  卢克  弄到我的脚啦
Darn it, Luke. That was my foot!
谁做了芝士通心粉然后吃完没洗
Who made macaroni and cheese and left it out?
抱歉  邓菲太太  是我跟卢克搞的
Sorry, Mrs. D. That was me and Luke.
但我要解释  我们当时嗨高了
But in our defense, we were high
然后被你的德国洗碗机吓到
and got spooked by your German dishwasher.
现在整个厨房都是蚂蚁
Well, now the entire kitchen is covered with ants,
我的身上也都是
and so am I.
祝你好运啦  家里热水用完啦
Well, good luck with that. No more hot water.
看来没救  我这脚趾甲得掉了
Yep! Gonna lose a toenail.
再见  今年的凉鞋季
There goes sandal season!
你喜欢吗
Do you love it?
天啊  你做完了好多
Oh, my God! You've gotten so much done.
我想在乔迁派对之前弄完嘛
Well, I wanted to finish it before the housewarming.
真是太好看了
It looks so good.
谢谢  我发誓这是新家的魔力
Thank you! I swear it's this place.
它让我如虎添翼
It... It makes me better at things.
一边喊着"绝杀"
at the laundry basket, yelled, "Money!"
差一点就投进去了呢
and it almost went in.
这是奇异又美妙的一个月
It's been a weird and wonderful month.
我们收养了个小男孩
We adopted a baby boy.
我们还搬进了新家
Yeah, and we moved into a new home,
我们超爱这里
which we love so much,
孩子的名字都是以这里的街名取的
we named our son after our street.
有这样的名字  他这辈子想当什么都可以
With a name like that, he can be anything he wants...
无论是四分卫  跑卫  甚至中线卫
a quarterback, a running back, a middle linebacker.
或许可以当踢球手
Maybe he could be a kicker.
你为什么不愿相信他能行呢  米奇尔
Why don't you believe in him, Mitchell?
真是要疯
This is crazy!
家里什么都没了
We're out of everything!
那是家里最后的早餐谷物吗
Is that the last of the cereal?
我们早就吃完了
Oh, we haven't had cereal in days.
这是奶粉加面包丁
This is formula over croutons.
你凭什么鄙视我
Don't... Don't judge me!
自打洗衣机坏掉之后
You've been wearing bathing suits for underwear
你就拿泳裤当内裤穿
since the washing machine broke.
我要是真有干净泳裤就好了
I wish I had a clean bathing suit.
我是把浴帽剪两个洞来穿
I had to cut leg holes into a shower cap.
我的牙齿上有沾到咖啡渣吗
Do I have coffee in my teeth?
阿尔文莫名其妙想在签合同之前跟我见一面
Arvin wants to meet before I sign the contract, for some reason.
我猜我知道这是为什么
I bet I know the reason why.
是因为他想跟你在一起
'Cause he wants to get with you.
他才没有呢  他马上就要变成我的上司了
No, he does not. He's about to be my boss.
所以他才想在签约前先跟你谈谈啊
Which is why he wants to talk before you sign.
这年头同事间谈恋爱是会惹麻烦的
Nowadays, you get in trouble for dating at work
除非是签约前就已经在一起了
unless it's a pre-existing relationship.
我会知道这个是因为公司有个超帅清洁工
I know this because I had to go to an HR thing
承受不了我调戏夸他几句
thanks to some smoking-hot janitor
害我被人事部训话
who can't take a compliment.
你是两个孩子的妈了  还是一样疯啊
Married mother of two, and you are insane.
阿尔文才没把我看成可交往对象呢
Arvin doesn't see me that way.
毕竟...  难道他有吗  你觉得
I mean, d-does he, do you think?
当然啦
Yes!
他一接近你就紧张还停不下嘴
He gets all nervous and yammery when he's around you.
你怎么到现在都还不知道你很有魅力
How do you still not know you're a babe?
毕竟你叫我暴脾气书呆足足20年
Well, I mean, you did call me a frumpy nerd for 20 years.
我不再那么叫你并不是因为我良心发现啊
Well, I didn't stop because I got nicer.
谁把奶粉配面包丁都吃完了
Who ate all the formula and croutons?
老爸老妈在哪  我们需要食物
Where are Mom and Dad? We need food.
等等  这是什么味道
Wait. What's that smell?
你还煎培根  他们能闻到好吗
Bacon? They're gonna smell that.
天啊  我忘了
Oh, my God! I didn't think about that!
快点吃掉证据
Quick! Eat it!
看  他们有食物
Hey! They have food!
还有咖啡  你们住在这里面吗
And coffee. Are you guys living in here?
妈  我要跟你借几件内裤
Mom, I need to borrow some underwear.
不能赖我  我试图阻止过他了
It's not my fault. I tried to stop him.
阻止谁  发生什么事啦
Stop who? What happened?
你的头发呢  怎么没了
Ay, your hair! Where is it?!
爸爸带我去让他的理发师剪头发
Dad took me to his barber.
真是太酷了
It was so cool!
你听过《花花公子》杂志吗
Have you heard of Playboy?
-我要杀了他  -还不止如此呢
- I'm going to kill him! - It gets worse.
他自作主张乱买了小卡与米奇尔的乔迁礼物
He went rogue on Mitch and Cam's housewarming gift.
所以他没有买
So, he didn't buy the coffee table book
洛杉矶演化史的那茶几装饰书吗
about Los Angeles through the decades?
快来看看
Check this out!
-我的天啊  -你看
- Oh, my God! - See?
这种反应可不是送一张一身灰的老头
You don't get that reaction from a picture of a dusty guy
在日落大道挑橘子的照片可以有的
picking oranges on Sunset Boulevard.
这是我这辈子见过最丑的东西
That's the ugliest thing I've ever seen.
但我喜欢我的新发型啊
But I like my hair!
宝贝我不是说你  你最完美了
No, not you, sweetie. You're perfect.
世界上没有任何一个女人配得上你
And no woman will ever deserve you.
我不知道你写不写日记
Hey, I don't know if you journal,
但我建议你记录一下今天
but you might want to dog-ear today's page
未来看心理医生用得上
for your future therapist.
杰  你不可以给同性恋买家具摆饰
Jay, you can't be buying home decor things for gays.
米奇尔跟小卡一定会讨厌死这玩意
Mitch and Cam are going to hate this thing!
才不会呢  他们两个一定会喜欢
No, they won't. The guys are gonna love it.
就像乔也喜欢他的新发型
Just like Joe loves his haircut.
大家一定会觉得他是长头虱去剃头发
Everybody's gonna think that he has lice.
希望不会
I hope not.
我爱死这房子了
I love this house!
你爱它吗  快说你爱它
Do you love it? Say you love it.
我爱啊
I do. I love it.
我爱它的动线
I love the flow.
采光  还有地点
I love the lights. I love the location.
而且地下室还有唱K房呢
There... There's even a karaoke room in the basement.
多有意思
So fun!
上一次我的地下室里有火辣麦克[麦克风]
The last time I had a hot Mike in my basement...
算了  还是等人多的时候再分享吧
You know what? I'm gonna wait till there are more people here.
宝宝醒了
Oh, oh, the baby's awake.
你想见见他吗
Do... Do you want to meet him?
我可以问他喜不喜欢我们送的礼物
I do. I can ask him if he liked our gift.
都没听到反馈
We never heard.
您好
Hello?
密苏里北部中央大学的体育部长
Athletic Director from the University of North Central Missouri.
好的  请问您找我有什么事情
Uh, yes, of course. How... How can I help you?
其实这通电话有点尴尬
This is a bit of an awkward call.
你应该也知道
As you know, you were the runner-up
你是我们主教练的第二名人选
for our head coaching job.
是的  我知道
Uh, yes, yes, and, uh, you know,
阿什利教练是个很棒的人  你们做了很棒的选择
Coach Ashley is a-a great guy, great choice.
我无怨无尤  我其实...
No hard feelings. I actually...
还送了一瓶恭贺的威士忌给他
I sent him a bottle of congratulatory scotch.
他喝了那瓶酒
Well, he drank it.
然后在记者会时
Then he did a press conference
他用了挺"生动"的语言
where he used some colorful language
称呼了一位女记者
to address a female reporter
还怪了犹太人一些事情
and blamed some things on the Jews.
我的老天
Oh, my.
我的重点是
The point is, uh,
如果你还有兴趣  那份工作就是你的了
the job is yours, if you still want it.
我知道这一切事发突然
I know this is coming at you fast,
我需要在今天结束之前知道答案
but I'll need an answer by the end of the day,
所以跟你先生谈谈后
so talk it over with the mister
给我个答复吧
and, uh, let me know.
谢谢你的来电  谢谢
Okay, thank... thank you very... thank you very much.
是啊  我知道  一切都好完美
I know. I know. It's all perfect.
感觉上天实现了我一切心愿
It's like the universe gave me everything I wanted.
好的  家庭会议  大家请坐下
Okay, family meeting.
迪兰  请坐  谢谢
Please. Sit down. Dylan, please. Thank you.
听我说
Now, um,
接下来这番话可能会有点伤感情
this is gonna sound harsh.
任何内心有感情的家长都不愿意说这些话
No... No parent with half a heart wants to say this,
所以克莱尔  你来说吧
so, Claire?
随便  我完全不介意说出这些话
Fine. I have no problem saying it.
家里住太多人了
There are too many people living in this house.
环境太脏乱
It's disgusting!
我怀疑有生物
I think there's something alive
是小槽槽而已啦
It's just Sinky.
你没打开厨余搅碎机吧
You didn't turn on the garbage disposal, did you?
你们其中一个得搬走
One of you has to move out.
我最近薪水刚大幅缩水
I-I just took a huge salary cut.
我现在真的没有办法搬家
So it is really not a good time for me to move.
我也是
Me neither.
我也不方便搬  我刚跟工作那边申请了休假
I just took a leave of absence from work
就因为我想多跟家人聚在一起
to spend more time with my family.
我有两个婴儿以及需要特殊照顾的丈夫
Well, I have two babies and a special needs husband.
是真的  我的病需要
It's true. I have a medical condition
住在能放下巨型床垫的房里
that requires a room big enough for a giant mattress.
如果你们之中没有人自愿搬走
Look, if one of you doesn't volunteer,
那就是你妈来选了
your mother's gonna have to pick someone.
海莉是长女  她一家有4个人
Well, Haley's the oldest. There's four of them.
而且说实话
And honestly, it's only a matter of time
她迟早会再怀上二胎
before she gets pregnant again.
尤其他还是个扭动者
Especially since he's a wiggler.
只有我们病人与家属才能这么说好吗
Whoa! We can say it.
艾丽克斯拥有最高的学历
Well, Alex is the one that has the most education.
我不该因为聪明而受到惩罚
I shouldn't be penalized for being smart.
我又没要选总统
I'm not running for president.
你呢  你不是申请了去上大学吗
What about you? Didn't you apply to college?
对啊  他们都没给我回复  大学真没礼貌
Yeah, and I never heard back from them. College is rude.
你们三个可以一边打扫家里
Okay! You can figure this out amongst the three of you
一边讨论答案
as you clean up the house.
今晚前我们要知道谁搬
We need a name by the end of the day.
肯定不会是我
Well, it's not gonna be me.
我都不敢想象跟我最好的死党分开
I just can't imagine being apart from my best friend.
卢克  你想得美
Nice try, Luke.
走
Oh, come on.
小卡  你看
Hey, Cam. Look!
小卡  小卡
Cam! Cam!
我们的邻居刚送来了这个给我们
Our neighbor just dropped this off.
太有心了  而且你猜怎么着
So sweet! And... And guess what.
她是个儿科医生
She's a pediatrician.
你说我们有多幸运
I mean, how lucky is that?
太棒了吧  这样就不用做婴儿防护
That's amazing! Now you don't have to ugly up the house
有香槟  有松露
There's champagne, there's truffles,
-还有鱼子酱  -城市佬啊
- there's caviar. - Ohh, city folk, huh?!
这年头没有人送老派的一篮苹果
I mean, whatever happened to a basket of apples
外加一张有心但错别字很多的卡片了吗
and a thoughtfully misspelled note?!
好啦  带我们参观你新家
Alright, give us a tour,
务必别忘了看小酒吧
- and make sure it includes the bar. - Yes!
我们先从唱K房开始
Okay, so let's start down in the karaoke room,
然后再往上一路参观到主卧
and then we'll work our way up to the master.
这听起来就像我心中梦幻约会的安排
Oh, sounds like my dream date!
抱歉  我是个单亲爸爸  从没机会出来玩
Sorry, I'm a single father. I never get out.
我们现在还这么说话吗
Is this still how we talk?
希望在楼下时
Okay, I hope the big earthquake that we're long overdue for
不会碰到加州早该震的地震
doesn't hit while you're down there!
你负能量爆棚啊
You're being so negative.
你是在抽什么风
What is wrong with you?
我必须得跟人倾诉
Okay, look, I have to tell someone,
但你不可以告诉别人  特别是米奇尔
but you cannot repeat it to anyone, especially Mitchell!
我刚收到了密苏里
I just got offered
那份梦寐以求的橄榄球工作邀约
the football job that I wanted in Missouri.
但你才刚搬进来新家啊
But you just moved in!
-我知道  -而且还领养了小婴儿
- I know. - With a newborn!
-我知道  -而且是你煽动做这两件事的
- I know! - And you were the one pushing for both!
我不需要你回顾  我的危机我还不清楚吗
I don't need a recap! It's my crisis!
我们到了
We're here!
你们来啦
Hey! Hey, guys!
乔  新发型不错啊
Wow! Joe, nice haircut!
看到了吧
See?
-我很想念他之前的发型  -很可爱
- I miss his old hair. - It's cute.
他看起来像《好人寥寥》里的汤姆·克鲁斯
He looks like Tom Cruise in "A Few Good Men."
我不介意找几个好男人"聊聊"
I wouldn't mind cruising a few good men.
再次道歉
Again, I'm sorry.
我把时间都花在孩子的生日派对上了
I spend all my time at kids' birthday parties.
我们族群现在真的没这么粗俗了吧
We're really probably better than this now, right?
-是的  -言归正传  我们给你们带了一份乔迁之礼
- Yeah. - Anyways, we brought you a housewarming gift.
-暂时将你们眼睛闭起来  -或许永远别睁开了
- Close your eyes. - Maybe never open them.
他是位老派酒保  来看看
He's an old-time barkeep. Now, check it out.
他是个大块头  就像小卡
He's a big guy, like Cam,
他有红色的头发  就像你
and he's got red hair, like you!
爸爸
Dad!
这就是我们需要的  一点奇思妙想
This is exactly what we needed... A little whimsy!
我超喜欢
I love it!
你才不呢  其他基佬们  告诉他
No, you don't. Other gays, tell him.
我们会和这家伙玩得很开心的
We're gonna have so much fun with this guy.
比如在独立日给他戴山姆大叔帽
We can throw a-an Uncle Sam hat on him
感恩节戴新移民帽
for the 4th of July, a pilgrim hat for Thanksgiving.
同志骄傲节的时候戴彩虹假发
Or a rainbow wig for... for pride.
这是件艺术品
Well, it's a piece of art.
你们不会想把他弄得傻乎乎的吧
I don't think you want to make it silly.
所以这个大家伙有名字吗
So, does this, uh, big fella have a name?
当然  因为他是小卡和米奇的合体
Sure does. Since he's a combo of Cam and Mitch,
所以叫卡奇
he's Kitsch.
是的没错  爸爸  太完美了
Oh, yeah! Yes, he is! Dad, it's perfect!
太棒了  现在米奇尔更开心了
Great. Now Mitchell's even happier.
我会在这个房子里终老的
I'm gonna die in this house.
-嗨  -艾丽克斯
- Hi. - Alex. Hi.
请进  请坐
Come in. Have a seat.
所以  我就直说了
So, I guess I'll just get right into it.
当我邀请你加入我的团队时
I-I didn't see this coming
我没预料到会有这事
when I asked you to work with me,
我想我有点担心
and I guess I'm sort of afraid...
这也解释了我举止尴尬的原因
which, uh, explains why I'm acting so awkwardly
以及我为什么说话停不下来
and why this sentence won't seem to end,
演员休·格兰特这么做就很讨喜
which is so delightful when Hugh Grant does it,
但我听起来就像胡言乱语
but I just sound like a raving...
-让我来说吧  -快请
- Let me stop you. - Please do.
我知道你想要说什么
I think I know what you're trying to say.
显然我们之间有暗潮汹涌的情愫
Uh, it appears there's some romantic tension between us,
你担心一旦我签了合同
and you're afraid that once I sign my contract,
我们就失去了发展的可能
we won't be able to act on it.
事实上
Uh... actually,
我只是打算告诉你
I was... I was just going to tell you
我们的项目移到瑞士了
that our project has been moved to Switzerland.
那你为什么支支吾吾
Well, then why were you hemming and hawing
还提到休·格兰特
and bringing up Hugh Grant,
这会让每个女孩都直接联想到爱情喜剧
which takes every girl right to rom-com?!
我担心你不想搬那么远
Well, I was afraid that you wouldn't want to move so far.
对你的辞职有责任
for you quitting your job.
忘记我刚刚说的  所以去瑞士对吧
Forget what I said! So, uh, Switzerland, huh?
-他们提供住房吗  -其实还真提供呢
- Do they pay for housing? - Um, actually, yeah.
太好了  这替我解决了一个大问题
Perfect. Perfect. That solves a big problem for me.
我加入  机场见
Yep. Count me in. See ya at the airport.
等下
Hold on!
看来有些事情
Um, it seems like there's something
我们得绕回去聊下
that we should circle back to.
不不  我没事
No, no, no. I'm fine.
艾丽克斯  我从没想过
Alex, I've never c-considered
和你交往的这种可能
a romantic relationship with you.
"太棒了"  还可以再回味下
Oh, great. Let's relive it.
我年龄比你大好多
I mean, I'm so much older.
我还和你姐姐交往过
I-I-I dated your sister.
但假如对你来说
But if it's something that isn't completely
交往不是毫无可能的话
out of the realm of possibility for you,
那么如果我说
then I'd be lying if I said
我觉得是不可能的  那就是撒谎
it was out of the realm of possibility for me.
-好的  -所以我们再聊聊之前的话吧
- Oh. Okay. - So, let's go back.
你是说如果我们之前就已经是恋爱关系
You're saying that if we had a pre-existing relationship,
更确切地说是以量子态形式存在的关系
or rather, a relationship that existed in a quantum state,
你不用为了我特地简化  但...
You don't have to dumb it down, but...
是的
but, yes,
我们就可以交往  从法律上来说
we'd be good to go, legally speaking.
那或者现在我们应该创造一些证据
Well, then, maybe we should create evidence now
来证明将来可能抑或不可能的恋爱关系
of a relationship that may or may not happen later?
什么证据
What kind of evidence?
我想我们可以发调情短信
I suppose we could exchange saucy texts.
-蛮符合逻辑的  -好吗
- Seems logical. - Yeah?
好的
Okay.
"你今天真好看"吗
"You look beautiful today"?
-太过了吗  -不不不
- Is that too much? - No! No, no, no.
天啊
Oh, my God!
你比我擅长太多了
You're so much better at this than I am!
或许我们应该来张合照
Maybe we should take a photo, you know?
证明我们以前就在一起了
Proof that we were together?
或者亲下脸颊
Uh, maybe a kiss on the cheek?
-是的  -好的
- Yeah! - Okay.
一二三
and one, two, three. Mwah.
天啊  对不起
Oh, God! Good God! I'm so sorry.
-不  -好吧
- No! - Wow! Oh! Okay.
又勾住了  真是好极了
Oh, good God. Oh, just great.
-二位好啊  -你好
- Hello, you two! - Hi!
-来一个法式咸派[吻]吧  -好欧式啊
- How about a little quiche? - Oh! How European.
罗纳多  你有什么秘方[你有什么秘密]
Oh, Ronaldo, what's your secret?
小卡得到了密苏里的教练职位邀约
Mm, Cam got offered that coaching job in Missouri,
-什么  -是的
- What?! - I know.
我们不再买汤了
We don't buy soup anymore
因为他无法完全合上嘴
because he can't close his mouth all the way.
小卡  你得到那个工作了
Cam! You got the job!
-你们要搬家了  -靠  罗纳多
- And you're moving. - Damn it, Ronaldo.
很明显  胡娇不是唯一一个
Apparently, Pepper's not the only one
合不上嘴的人
who can't keep his mouth closed.
快走  去上你的小菜吧
Go. Serve your little apps.
我不敢相信
I can't believe this.
别紧张  我会拒绝的
Okay, don't panic. I'm... I'm gonna turn it down.
真的吗  但这是你一直想要的
Oh, really? But it's what you've always wanted.
我知道  但米奇尔  他
I know, but Mitchell, he's...
我从没见过他这么开心
I've never seen him so happy.
我不能毁了这一切
And I can't ruin that.
我都不打算告诉他我收到邀约了
I'm... I'm not even gonna tell him I got the offer.
看到你们俩离开
of the idea of you guys leaving,
但是如果你不告诉米奇尔
but if you don't tell Mitchell,
你最终会怨他的
you're gonna end up resenting him.
不  我  我不是这种人
No, that's... that's not how I'm built.
我一旦决定  就一条路走到底  绝不回头
I make decisions, move forward, don't look back.
绝不后悔
No regrets.
大家听我说一下
Hey, everyone?
我要感谢你们来参观
Um, I just want to thank you all for coming
我们的新家
to see our new home
认识一下我们的宝贝新室友雷克斯福德
and meet our precious new roommate, Rexford.
我还要感谢我最棒的丈夫  小卡
And, uh, I also want to thank my wonderful husband, Cam,
都是在他的领导下  才有现在这一切
who really led the charge and made all of this possible.
这是我人生中最幸福的时刻
I-I couldn't be happier right now,
这一切都是因为他
and it's all because of him.
要是他放弃
Now, if I could just get him
跟我抢被子就更好了
to give up hogging the covers, huh?
我为你放弃的还不够多吗
'Cause I haven't given up enough for you!
太尴尬了
This is so embarrassing.
我刚意识到罗纳多是要给我法式咸派
I just realized Ronaldo was offering me quiche.
所以你本来都不打算告诉我你收到邀约吗
So, y-you were never gonna tell me you got offered the job?
因为看到你好像很开心
It's just that you seemed so happy,
我没办法要求你放弃这一切
and I couldn't ask you to give that up.
小卡  这几年你一直想搬到
Cam, you've been wanting to move closer
离你家近点的地方
to your family for years,
这又是你梦想的工作
and... and this is your dream job.
不
No.
不  这是换我来支持你的机会
No. T-This is my chance to be there for you.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
只要你在我身边
as... as long as you're there by my side.
永远都在
Always.
好啦  我们喝点香槟来庆祝一下
Alright, now let's celebrate with some champagne!
好啊
Yeah!
米奇尔  米奇尔  你说得太感人了
Mitchell. Mitchell. That was beautiful.
所有人都盯着我看
Well, everyone was looking at me.
我特么还能说什么
What the fuck was I supposed to say?
你怎么样了
How are you feeling?
没有他们整天在我们家晃  会感觉挺怪的吧
Uh, it's gonna be weird without them being here all the time.
还有他们新领养的小孩
Plus, they got the new kid.
可怜的小家伙
Poor guy's gonna grow up
得看着密苏里衣柜长大
with those Missouri closets,
会以为那里的衣柜是正常的呢
thinking that's normal.
米奇毫不犹豫地决定离开真令人感动啊
It was sweet how Mitch didn't have to think twice about going.
他自己说的  轮到他去支持小卡了
Well, it's like he said, it's his turn to support Cam.
这差不多也是我一直努力为你做的
Almost the same thing I'm trying to do for you,
但我这样只会惹你生气
except I'm pissing you off.
因为你总是不按我想要的方式来啊
Because you won't do anything the way that I would do it!
我没听到有人抱怨啊
I don't see anyone else complaining.
这就是最糟糕的地方  没人需要我
That's the worst part... that nobody needs me.
都2020年了  我不该被白人老头抢走工作
It's 2020. I shouldn't be losing jobs to an old white man.
曼尼想家的时候
When Manny gets homesick,
你觉得他会给谁打电话
who do you think he's gonna call?
乔做噩梦的时候  他会找谁
When Joe has a nightmare, who does he want?
我坐在这里
And when I'm sitting here
为米奇尔要离开而伤心
already sad about Mitchell leaving,
你觉得我希望谁到这屋里陪我
who do you think I want to walk into this room?
-我吗  -当然了
- Me? - Of course!
我知道是怎么回事了
And I think I know what's going on here.
你为了工作感到愧疚  不要这样
You're feeling guilty about working. Don't.
你觉得我以前工作会因为你在家
Do you think I ever felt guilty working
操持一切而愧疚吗
while you held down the fort here?
-你当然没有  -是的  所以现在轮到你
- You sure didn't. - No, and now it's time
去外面的世界闯荡一番了
for you to go out into the world and crush it.
然后你在家操持一切
While you hold down the fort
还要保持美丽哦
and look pretty?
我可不只是花瓶而已
Well, I'm not just a sex object.
我还有别的强项
I have other gifts.
-这一天真够呛  -是啊
- That was a crazy day. - Yeah.
我今晚可能都要睡不着了
I think I'm gonna be up for a while tonight.
我载着你兜风  直到你睡着
and I'll drive you around till you fall asleep?
我不想  我想睡在我们家里
I don't. I want to sleep in our house,
跟我们的孩子  所有孩子一起
with our kids... all of them.
今天看了米奇尔跟小卡
With what's going on with Mitchell and Cam,
我觉得家人正在逐渐离我们而去
I just feel like we're losing enough family as it is.
巧了
It's funny.
我也这样觉得
I was feeling that, too.
你之前把话说得太绝了
You came down so hard on them earlier.
太好了  你们回来了
Oh, good. You're home.
对  你弟弟跟姐姐在吗
Yeah. Are your brother and sister here?
我要跟你们聊一下关于住家的情况
I want to talk about this whole living situation.
-对  -其实问题解决了
- Yeah. - Actually, problem solved.
-什么  -我要搬到瑞士
- What? - I'm moving to Switzerland.
-什么  -他们要把我的研究团队转移过去
- What? - They're transferring my research team there.
而且有包住跟很多其他的东西
I get housing and everything.
所以你们的问题也解决了
So you're good.
你是说瑞士卷那个瑞士吗
Like, hot chocolate Switzerland?
-你说了我们的事情了吗  -只说了我的
- Did you tell them our news? - Uh, just mine.
迪兰跟我也要搬出去了
Dylan and I are moving out, too.
但你们不是非搬不可啊
Oh, but you don't have to!
我们想搬  你们说得对
Well, we want to. You guys are right.
我们是该走了
It's time for us to go.
我们算过了  发现我们有一百万美元
We did the math, and we realized we had a million dollars.
然后让艾丽克斯帮我们验算了一下  发现没有
Then we had Alex check the math, and turns out we don't,
但是足以住一套小公寓了
but we do have enough for a cute apartment.
现在大家不做动物测试了
Now that they don't test on animals,
我工作的时候可以做临床试验赚点外快
I've made extra money doing clinical trials at work.
挺费时的  但是迷宫挺好玩[动物实验]
The hours are long, but the mazes are fun.
太好了  你们都在
Sweet. You're all here.
没事了  我会搬出去
Everyone can relax. I'll be the one who goes.
不不不  卢克
Oh, no, no, Luke.
-没关系的  -不不不  我之前撒谎了
- It's okay. - No, no, no, no. I lied before.
我其实有收到俄勒冈大学的消息
I actually did hear back from the University of Oregon.
我被录取了
I got in.
我们为你骄傲
We're so proud of you!
-太棒了  卢克  -是啊  恭喜
- That's amazing, Luke! - Yeah. Congrats.
等等  你们都要搬出去吗
Wait. You're... You're all moving out?
是吗  我们都要吗
Really? We are?
-是的  -好奇怪
- Yeah. - Weird.
阿尔文的电话
Oh! It's Arvin.
抱歉  我得去接一下
Sorry, I've got to respond to it.
是工作上的事
It's a work thing.
我要去准备下  有个约会
I've got to get ready. I've got a date.
他们又开始了
Oh, there they are.
卢克  我在里面
Oh! Luke, I'm in here!
-你在干嘛  -出去
- What are you doing?! - Oh, get out!
我会想念这一切的
I am gonna miss this.
我也是
Me too.
大家都走了
Everybody's gone.
是这样的
Look.
我还没有给学校回复
I haven't called the college yet.
我想先跟你商量
I wanted to talk to you first.
我知道你刚才在楼上是装大度  而且...
I know you were being generous up there, and...
你知道我的  我在哪里都能开心的
You know me. I-I can be happy anywhere.
是真的
No, seriously.
过一段时间  我就会把这个地方忘干净了
After some time, I-I'll forget all about this place.
我们的儿子是以这条街命名的
We named our son after the street.
那我们就把他的名字改成新的街名
So we'll just change his name to the new street.
教练的住处是在十三大道
The coach's house is at the intersection
和焦玉米巷的交叉口
of Route 13 and Burnt Corn Lane.
天啊  我们这是要干什么
Dear God, what are we doing?
要是没人喜欢我怎么办  要是我找不到工作怎么办
W-What if no one likes me? What if I can't find a job?
那里有艺术电影院吗
A-Are there art house theaters?
我们搬家的事情讨论得如何了
Hey. Where are we on this move?
亲爱的  我和二爸现在
Well, that's what Daddy and I
正在商量这件事呢
are talking about right now, sweetie.
因为我有个大报告周二要交
Cause I have a major project due on Tuesday,
我不是说我还没开始做
and I'm not saying I haven't started it,
但如果你们非要看我目前进度的话
but if you asked to see what I've done so far,
我确实没东西可以给你们看
there wouldn't be anything.
我们搬
We're going.
我会需要一点时间调整
I-I'm gonna need a little time to adjust,
但是我们...  我们要搬走
but we... we are going.
你没意见吗
Are you okay with that?
我没事  我会改造一下自己
Totally. I'll reinvent myself.
我要把头发染成蓝色
I'm gonna dye my hair blue
然后随身带一只情感支持宠物猪
and carry around an emotional support pig.
小卡  通知学校吧
Cam, well, call the college.
好  我就是希望这是正确的决定
Okay! I just want this to be the right thing.
如果最后对这个家不好的话
If... If this ends up hurting the family,
-我不会原谅自己的  -不会的
- I would never forgive myself. - No, no.
我们很强大的  我们会没事的
We're stronger than that, okay? We're gonna be fine.
没错
Yeah.
现在不是时候  莉莉
Not... Not now, Lily.
反正你们最后还是要唱的  快点唱吧
You guys are gonna end up singing. Just get to it.
不好意思  这位小姐
Excuse me, young lady.
我们现在可是在很严肃地谈话  好吗
We're... We're having a-a serious conversation here, okay?
不要把我们跟老套的情侣混为一谈
Do not reduce us to a couple stereotypical...
♪ 我的挚爱 ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ 你是我生命中的唯一 ♪
♪ There's only you in my li-ife ♪
♪ 是黑暗里的光影 ♪
♪ The only thing that's bright ♪
为什么总是让我唱女声部分
Why do I always have to sing the female part?
♪ 我的初恋 ♪
♪ My first love ♪
♪ 你的一切左右着我的呼吸 ♪
♪ You're every breath that I take ♪
我真应该好好考虑一下再放歌
I didn't think this through.
♪ 控制着我的脚步 ♪
♪ You're every step I make ♪
我不喜欢当第一个到派对的人
I do not like being the first person at a party.
其实你是最后一个到的
Uh, oh, actually, you're the last one.
对  萨尔  大家都走了
Yeah, Sal, everybody's gone.
什么  扫兴
What?! Boo!
基佬们没孩子之前都可有意思了
Gays used to be so fun, before kids.
来吧  我们来喝烈酒
Come on! Let's do shots!
你们知道吗  这个房子离我的新家只有一个街区
You know this house is only a block from my new place.
其实也不是我的
Well, it's not "mine,"
但是我能免费住在那儿
but I get to stay there for free
因为我允许房东从摄像头看我
cause I let the guy who owns it watch me on webcams.
我会经常过来的
I'm gonna be coming over all the time!
太棒了
Yay!
这边的笑脸表情包可以帮我照看狗和小孩
And, um, Happy Face Emoji here can babysit my dogs and kid.
你们会做饭的  对吧
And you guys cook, right?
-其实我现在已经觉得搬走挺好的了  -那就好
- Actually, I'm feeling better about the move already. - Good.
所以  真的到了分别的时刻了吗
Oh. So, this is really it?
我们会超想你们
We are gonna miss you all so much.
给你  我希望你能看看这个
And, here, I want you to read this,
但要等到我走之后
but not until after I leave.
你这个好看的  吃玉米长大的坏蛋
you beautiful, corn-fed son of a bitch?
你们会回来看看的  对吧
You guys are gonna visit, right?
当然  而且你们也可以来看我们
Of course. And you all are gonna visit us.
只是几趟很短的航程
It's just a couple quick flights
加上从机场打个"油步"
and a short Goober ride from the airport.
-他刚刚是不是说...  -等一下  外公不来吗
- Did he just say... - Wait, isn't Grandpa coming?
他昨晚已经跟我们道别了
He said goodbye last night.
-你们也知道他不喜欢这种离别抒情的事  -没错
- You know how he hates these things. - Yeah.
真不敢想象我就要失去过去的滑冰搭档了
I can't believe I'm losing my old skating partner.
每当你看到我们以前的奖杯
Well, whenever you look at our old trophy,
都要想起来我们以前是多好的搭档  好吗
just remember what a good team we were, huh?
我说过我不会哭的
I said I wasn't gonna cry.
-你确实没哭  -对  这就叫坚强
- And you're not. - Yeah. It's called strength.
我不能错过这个
I couldn't miss this.
而怨恨我
because your son's leaving.
我的两个儿子都要走了
Both my sons are leaving.
杰  杰
Oh, Jay! Jay!
一个家庭随着时间过去可以发生很多事
A lot can happen to a family over the years.
新的成员
New additions...
新的挣扎
...new struggles.
给我点时间
Give me a second.
你不会给每个瞬间都留下标记
You don't always mark the moments,
因为你太忙于照料生活
because you're too busy taking care of life.
有时你最好的选择
Best you can do sometimes
就是让自己珍惜每一个...
is remind yourself to cherish every single...
密苏里有龙卷风预警
There's a tornado warning in Missouri.
你们居然记得我的生日
You guys remembered my birthday!
惊喜
Surprise.
能有这多余的时间待在一起真好
It's nice we have this extra time together,
多亏了幸运的龙卷风
thanks to that lucky tornado.
龙卷风袭击了一所小学  菲尔
It hit an elementary school, Phil.
不过学校里没人
Well, no kids were there.
今天是猎松鼠季的开幕日
It's opening day of squirrel-hunting season.
杰  过来跟家人一起坐下吧
Jay, do you want to come and join your family?
杰  他最近总是这样
Jay! He's been like this a lot lately...
沉浸在自己的世界
in his own world.
这段时间确实很难熬
Well, it's a tough time.
米奇和小卡要搬走了
Mitch and Cam leaving,
曼尼下周出发
Manny heading out next week,
加上我因为要去沙漠里的一个蹦床集会
plus I'm missing his birthday for a tumbling
会缺席他的生日宴
congress in the desert.
你说不定听说过呢  叫翻人节
You've probably heard of it. Turning Man?
别忘了乔和我
And don't forget that Joe and I
要回哥伦比亚度过整个夏天
are leaving to Colombia for the whole summer.
假如你们开车路过我家
If you drive past my house
从窗户看到我在家里穿着袜子到处"滑冰"
and see me sock-sliding past the window
手里还拿着杯苏格兰威士忌
with a scotch in my hand,
那是我正在应对悲痛
that's just how I deal with grief.
我们不想急着离席
Not to, uh, rush this,
但我们搬新家的打包工作延误了好多
but we are very behind on packing for our new place.
我们还得装箱所有婴儿用品
You know, we still need to box up all the baby stuff,
所有床品和那本书
our linens, our book.
别那么紧张
Well, don't stress out too much.
那么  再次告别
So... This is goodbye again.
得花点时间才能重新感伤起来
It's gonna take a minute to ramp back up to all the emotion...
过来抱抱  过来抱抱
Get in here. Get in here.
抱歉  松开一下
Sorry. One second. One second.
这次是洪水警报
Flood warnings this time.
航线上还发现了一大群蝗虫
Oh, and a swarm of locusts has been spotted in the flight path.
我们这是要搬到圣经旧约里去吗
What part of the Old Testament are we moving to?
是活物吗
Is it alive?
不是
No.
是剪刀吗
Is it scissors?
是
Sure.
可你刚才说比钢琴还重
No, but you said it was heavier than a piano!
我只希望游戏赶快结束
I just want this to be over.
-我们别玩游戏了行吗  -行
- Can we be done with games? - Yes.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
这里放醋了吗
Is there vinegar in here?
恭喜你  你死了
Congratulations. You're dead!
没看到饮料的制作过程  你就不该喝
Never take a drink if you haven't watched it be made.
他看了一期叫《游轮末日》的特别节目
Uh, he saw this special called "You Cruise, You Lose,"
现在他确信
and he's convinced something bad
我旅行时会遭遇不测
is going to happen to me on my trip.
假如这真的被下药  你已经被装上货船
If this had been the real thing, you'd be on a container ship
被运往的黎波里奴隶市场了
halfway to the slave markets in Tripoli.
我们的车马上就到
Oh, our car's a minute away.
放过我的亚麻西装
Lay off my linen suit.
它已经皱得像我最爱的猪
It's already as wrinkled as my favorite pig
减肥后皱巴巴的皮
when she lost all that weight.
我们能在楼梯上最后再拍张照吗
Oh, c-can we take one last picture by the staircase?
不要太感性  流程你们都熟悉
Alright, no gushiness. You know the drill.
-别回头  -好主意
- Do not look back. - Yeah, good idea.
如果看到他们站在窗后
You know, I don't think I could take the sight
满是泪水的脸庞  我可能会承受不住
of their tear-streaked faces pressed against the glass.
从很多角度来看  我们要更轻松些
In many ways, it's easier for us.
我们要去展开新冒险
I mean, we're off to a new adventure,
而他们被困在这个无聊阴郁的老地方
and they're stuck in the same dull, mirthless...
你们拍全家福不带我们
You're taking a family picture without us?!
这下我们可以毫无留恋地远行了
Okay, well, you have made leaving a lot easier...
因为很显然这家人需要分开一段时间
because, clearly, what this family needs is some time apart.
走
Let's...
我们有谁没料到这一幕吗
Did any of us really not think that was gonna happen?
这次是冰雹
Hail this time.
米奇尔  既然有这个机会
Okay, Mitchell, now that we have this moment,
我很确定滑冰奖杯在你那
I'm pretty sure you have the skating trophy.
我最近打包了所有行李两次
Um, I recently packed up my entire house twice.
怎么会没发现我唯一的体育奖杯  克莱尔
I think I would notice my only sports trophy, Claire.
我什么都没打包
Well, I haven't packed up my house at all...
奖杯不在我这
I don't have the trophy!
你们俩都没有奖杯
Neither of you has it.
当时你们无休止地争论该摆在谁房间
You argued endlessly about which room it was going into
直到你们老妈抢走奖杯
until your mother grabbed it
把它重新捐给了滑冰场
and donated it back to the skating rink.
好吧  我们只有晚上九点的航班可乘了
Okay, well, now our only option is the 9:00 P.M.
幸运的是  这是直达堪萨斯城的航班
Fortunately, it's a direct flight into Kansas City
然后换乘美猪铁路短程就好了
and then just a short hop on HamTrak, so...
-你说的是"美猪"吗  -好吧
- Did you just say "Ham"... - Fine.
大家各忙各的  我们晚点在这重聚
Everybody get on with their day. We'll meet back here later.
对了  我们特别喜欢新家
Oh, we love our new place, by the way.
再次谢谢你帮我们跟房东说好话
Thanks again for putting in a good word for us with the owner.
他只是需要一颗定心丸
Yeah, he just needed some reassurance,
毕竟迪兰的大部分钱
considering most of Dylan's money
都拿去买了餐厅代金券
is tied up in Dave & Buster's gift cards.
比存在银行里安全
Safer than banks.
我只是出于好奇...
So, just because I'm curious...
是的  是运牲口的火车  但人也能乘
Yeah, it's a livestock train, but people ride it, too.
但别担心  我们跟参展的猪一起坐头等舱
But don't worry, we're in first class with the show hogs.
米奇尔  我们为了这奖杯
Mitchell, we skated our little hearts out
拼尽心血表演《饥饿如狼》
to "Hungry Like the Wolf" for this thing.
我要拿走  见鬼  锁住了
I'm taking it. Damn it, it's locked.
你带我来偷东西吗
You brought me here to steal?!
我不能进监狱  我是同性恋检察官
I can't go to jail. I am a gay prosecutor.
监狱里没有属于我的帮派
There's no prison gangs for that.
放松点  帮我把风就行
Relax. Just keep an eye out.
你在做什么  你居然会撬锁
W-what are you doing? You-you know how to pick a lock?
卢克总是被什么东西锁住
Luke's always getting locked into something.
我还要偷看海莉的日记
Between that and trying to break into Haley's diary,
我都成专家了
I'm kind of a pro.
顺带一提  多谢你给她买避孕药
By the way, thanks for getting her on birth control.
这不是舅舅该做的吗
Oh, yeah, what are uncles for?
保安来了  装没事
Oh, security. Be cool.
我们坐在这个位置  度过了多少个夜晚
How many nights did we spend in these exact same positions?
我用手电筒做作业
Me doing homework by flashlight,
你为了不去上体育课  瞎编各种病
and you inventing new illnesses to get out of P.E.
是啊  记得我染上"方包菌"那次吗
Oh, yeah! Remember when I had frumbles?
还记得卢克做噩梦时
How about when Luke would have nightmares
拖着睡袋过来吗
and drag his sleeping bag in here?
我们等他睡着后
We'd wait till he fell asleep,
点上蜡烛  戴上恶魔面具
light candles, put on devil masks,
叫醒他
and wake him up.
有我们做姐姐真不容易
Couldn't have been easy having us as big sisters.
那...
So...
或许我们在都搬走前
maybe before we all move out,
应该再整他一次  对吧
we should mess with him one last time, right?
当然
Oh, yeah.
那是2005年
It was 2005,
我们很想养只狗狗
and we desperately wanted a dog.
于是我们拍了一段视频  想证明给爸妈看
So we made a video to convince our parents
我们能当负责任的铲屎官
that we could be responsible dog owners.
当然了  狗狗是由6岁的卢克扮的
The dog, of course, was played by a 6-year-old Luke.
那年夏天他本来就长皮癣
He'd already had ringworm that summer,
所以扮起狗来得心应手
so he had an entryway into the role.
卢克
Luke!
那是什么
What was that?
你弄坏了  老妈会发疯的
You cracked it. Mom's gonna go insane!
她每年母亲节都要重看一遍
She watches it every year on Mother's Day!
惨了  惨了  世界末日啊
This is bad. This is bad. This is bad!
-我们该怎么办  -这个办法可能行不通
- What should we do? - This probably won't work,
-不过...  -快说啊
- but... - Say it!
我们可以让你再扮一次狗狗  重录一遍
We could re-create it with you as the dog again...
你犯了这么大的错  应该表示一下歉意
...as a sweet gesture to make up for what you've done.
等等
Wait a minute.
汪汪的耳朵刚好就出现在这里吗
The Woofie ears just happen to be here?
我一定是全世界最幸运的小王八蛋了
I must be the luckiest bastard alive.
我们开拍吧
Let's do this.
-密苏里啊  -对
- So, Missouri, huh? - Yeah.
其实  我...
You know, I'm... I'm
我对搬过去这事还挺乐观的
actually feeling pretty good about it.
那边有很多很棒的就业机会
There are a lot of really great career opportunities there.
凭我的工作经历  我说不定能当上法官呢
And with my experience, I could become a judge.
最近对你来说也挺令人兴奋吧
It's a pretty exciting time for you, too, huh?
收纳公司的新工作
Yeah? Big new job at that storage-and-container company...
-对  -孩子们要搬出去
- Yeah. - ...kids moving out.
没有
They're not.
但我以为他们...
But I thought that they...
-真的没有  -好吧
- They're not. - Oh! Okay.
都还没正式去上班
Haven't even started the job yet,
你就已经开始"分隔"情感了
and you're already compartmentlizing.
而你就已经开始评判[法官]别人了
And you're already judging.
开不了
This isn't working.
要不算了吧  走吧
Hey, let's just forget it. Come on.
天啊
Oh. Oh, my God.
抓[爪]娃娃机
The claw machine.
来嘛
Come on!
还记得我们以前抓技多高强吗
Remember how we killed at that?
-是啦  -你负责控制爪子  我在侧面侦察地形
- Yeah. Yeah. - You on the claw, me scouting from the side?
等等
Wait a minute.
-举高我  -什么
- Give me a boost. - What?
快  举高我
Yeah, give me a boost.
好了  这是我们的机会
Okay, alright. This is our chance.
现在往下  伸进去
Okay. Now go down, down.
我们加菲猫存钱罐里的身家就是这样赔光的
That's how we lost the Garfield bank.
你快成功了
You almost have it.
别担心  这次我们会分享奖杯
Okay, don't worry. This time, we'll share it.
不过先放我家
But I get it first.
天啊  太好玩了
Oh, my God. That was so fun!
除了你  我不会跟任何人做这种刺激事
Oh, I never do stuff like this with anybody but you.
也因为我是个有道德观念的成年人
Well, also because I'm an adult with ethics.
我们是最佳搭档
We make a great team.
老天  我刚刚想到
Oh, my God. It just hit me.
这也许是我们最后一次...
This might be the last time that we...
不不不  别说  我们已经道别过两次了
No, no, no. No, no. We already said goodbye twice.
别搞得太伤感
Keep it light.
我最好的一些回忆都是和你一起在这里发生的
It's just that some of my best memories are of you and me here.
好了  就这样  我说完了
That... There, that's it. I'm done.
你会不会...  渴望[饥饿]拥有更多
Would you say... you're hungry for more?
饥饿是指...
Hungry like...
-这比我印象中更色情  -对
- This is more sexual than I remember it being. - Yeah.
我开始觉得当年我们获胜是歪打正着
I'm starting to think we won for the wrong reasons.
最后一罐了
That's it.
我们终于把我的辣酱吃光了
We're finally out of my hot sauce.
杰  你饿不饿
Jay, are you hungry?
杰
Jay?
他怎么回事啊
What's wrong with him?
家里一切都会没事的吧  妈妈
Is everything gonna be okay, Mommy?
你吓着我们了
You're scaring us.
没事的  小家伙
Oh, it's okay, buddy.
傻逼
Idiot!
希望你喜欢在加尔各答街头跳舞挣钱
I hope you like dancing for coins on the streets of Calcutta.
我在车库又找到一些辣酱
I found more hot sauce in the garage.
超辣的[西语]
Muy caliente.
好险  我差点就露馅了
Oof! I almost gave it away, there.
我正准备给歌洛莉亚一个大惊喜
I got a big surprise for Gloria in the works.
我在学西班牙语
I'm learning Spanish.
我一有机会就有戴上无线耳机
Every chance I get, I pop my earbuds in,
学几课
learn a few lessons.
杰  过来跟家人一起坐下吧
Jay, do you want to come and join your family?
它还有个很酷的功能
Program's even got a cool feature.
无论我想学什么短语  只需用英语说一遍
Any phrase I want to learn, I just say it in English,
就能在耳机里听到"西语"版本
and it spits it right back at me in Espanol.
抱歉  我是指"西班牙语"啦
I'm sorry, I mean "Spanish."
我常常把英语和西语说混了而不自知
I go back and forth without even noticing.
傻了吧唧[西语]
Loco!
你确定现在借你的挂烫机
Hey, you're sure now's not a bad time
不会不方便吧
to borrow your garment steamer?
当然不会  这玩意简直是神器
Of course not. And this thing's a marvel.
谁能料到拳王乔治·福尔曼除了做烤炉还有这一招
Who knew George Foreman had one more in him after his grill?
你来了真的太好了
I'm so glad that you're here.
你记得我之前跟你说过的  我那个小问题吗
Do you remember that little problem that I told you I had?
每个人都会做那种梦
Everyone has dreams like that.
日本人甚至专门有一类漫画是这种题材的
The Japanese have a whole genre of comic books about it.
不不不  是关于杰
No, no, no. It's about Jay.
我不知道他是开始耳聋了
I don't know if he's losing his hearing
还是有抑郁之类的
or he's depressed or what.
他很可能对我难以启齿  但是...
Probably he's ashamed to talk to me, but...
但是对他最好的朋友不会  不用再说了
But not to his best friend. Say no more.
你只需去给意面锅盛水并煮沸就行了
I just need you to fill a spaghetti pot with water and boil it.
只是给小卡烫西装的备用计划
Oh, it's a backup for Cam's suit.
我已经对乔治·福尔曼失去信心了
I lost all confidence in George Foreman
上次他的美白牙贴灼伤了我的牙龈
after his teeth-whitening system burned my gums.
两位  谢谢
Table for two, please.
你是我的服务员吗
Are you my waiter?
杰  你怎么样
Hey, Jay. How you doing?
这不是我想要的
This isn't what I wanted.
我知道大家都要走了  你的心情可能有点低落
I know you might be feeling a little down with everybody leaving,
但这又不是世界末日  对吧
but it's not the end of the world, right?
我完了[点餐完了]
I'm finished here.
别说这种话啊
Don't you talk like that.
能给我一把勺子吗[勺式抱抱]
Could I please have a spoon?
你需要什么我都奉陪
Whatever you need...
兄弟
buddy.
-怎么了  -你他妈在干什么啊
- What?! - What the hell are you doing?!
怎么  不是你要求的吗
What?! I thought that's what you wanted!
虽然跟你的个性略有不符
Slightly out of character, yes,
但现在是情绪泛滥的时候
but it's an emotional time!
-我很担心你  -我没事  菲尔
- I was worried about you. - I'm fine, Phil.
我也在改变
And I'm changing, too.
我在学西班牙语  好给歌洛莉亚惊喜
I'm learning Spanish to surprise Gloria!
当然了
Of course.
好吧  既然给我们
Well, then, having added
事故频出的翁婿史又增添了新的尴尬故事
yet another embarrassing incident to our storied history,
我还是先闪了吧
I will slink out.
今天对你来说肯定也很不容易
Today can't be easy for you either.
我很感激你对我的担心  但是...
And I appreciate you're worried about me, but...
或许你可以想想
maybe start thinking...
你希望你人生的下个篇章是怎样的
what you want your next chapter to be.
谢谢你  杰
Thanks, Jay.
歌洛莉亚  歌洛莉亚
Oh, uh, Gloria? Gloria?
我注意到你的睫毛膏完全没被哭花
I noticed your mascara was still intact,
所以我猜你一定还没看我写的信
so I assume you haven't had a chance to read my note.
是的  还没有
No, not yet.
那对我们两个来说都会很不容易
Oh, well, you know, it will be hard on both of us,
但是  择时不如撞时
but there's... there's no time like the present.
歌洛莉亚  或许你没注意到
Oh, uh, G-Gloria, maybe you didn't notice
我的信还有第二面
that there's a second side to my note.
不如这样吧  我给你播放
And you know what? Maybe it would help
我在写这封信时配的音乐  能帮你烘托情绪
if I played the music that I used while I was composing it.
真有爱
So nice.
什么  有爱而已吗
What? Nice?
这简直是最完美的道别信
It was the perfect goodbye letter.
简直是《恋恋笔记本》和《飞屋环游记》前十分钟的合体
It's "The Notebook" meets the first 10 minutes of "Up."
那足以让你咒骂上帝
It was enough to make you curse God
赐予你爱的能力
for giving you the ability to love.
不过是一首每行以我的姓名字母开头的诗而已
It was a poem where every line started with a letter of my name.
好吧  我知道你在干什么
Okay, alright, I... I know what you're doing.
你在给你的感情竖立一道墙
You're putting up walls around your... your feelings,
因为你从情感上还没有准备好
because you're not emotionally prepared
跟你如此深爱的一个人告别
to let go of someone you love so dearly.
对哦  他也要离开了
Oh, yeah. He's leaving, too.
21年
21 years.
5份职业
Five careers.
两任丈夫
Two husbands.
他是我身边唯一未变的存在
He was the only constant.
我现在无法因此向他哭泣
I can't start crying to him about this now,
-因为我一哭可能就止不住了  -没错
- because I might never stop. - Yes.
我不希望让他因此更加难受
I don't want to put all that on him.
我懂  但这种情感必须有个宣泄渠道啊  歌洛莉亚
Yes, I know, but those feelings have to go somewhere, Gloria.
你何不学学我的做法  都写下来呢
Why don't you do what I did... put them in writing?
-谢谢你  小卡  -不
- Thank you, Cam. - No.
不  歌洛莉亚
No, Gloria.
我谢你才对
Thank you.
谢谢你让我成为
Thank you for allowing me
过去12年你精神觉醒的指引者
to be your guide to spiritual awakening the last 12 years.
我真的  深感荣幸
It has been... a true privilege.
你在说些什么呢
What are you talking about?
我们最多也就单独相处过七八次而已
We've been alone maybe like eight times.
嘘
Shh.
妈咪  爹地
Hi, Mommy and Daddy.
我们知道你们认为我们无法照顾好一只狗
We know you don't think that we can take care of a dog,
但你们还没见过我们的狗狗汪汪
but you haven't met our dog, Woofie.
-汪  -别乱叫  汪汪
- Woof! - No barking, Woofie.
别担心  我们永远都记得
And don't worry, we'll always remember
给它喂食  让它保持健康
to feed him and keep him healthy.
里面是放了药吗
Is there a pill in here?
所以你不想要油光发亮的毛皮吗
So, you don't want a shiny coat?
别担心  我们会确保它跟别的狗狗相处融洽
And don't worry, we'll make sure he gets along with other dogs.
几小时后再见咯
See you in a few hours.
几小时吗
Hours?
你们可能担心
You guys are probably worried
它会把家里弄得很脏
he's going to get the house all dirty.
我们知道如何处理这个问题
Well, we know how to handle that.
看到了吧  我们能做到的
So, as you can see, we can do this.
我们知道养狗费心费力
We know a dog's a lot of work,
但我们不必独自承担
but we'll never have to do it alone.
没错  我们三个永远会一起的
Yeah, it will always be the three of us.
永远
Always.
结束
The end.
你们知道你们可以随时联系我的  对吧
You guys know you can call me anytime, right?
去瑞士也很方便  所以...
And it's easy to visit Switzerland, so...
我还是可以向你寻求恋爱建议的  对吧
And I can still count on you for relationship advice, right?
我可不想成为那种可悲的男人
I don't want to become one of those pathetic guys
任由女人操控他们
that lets women manipulate them.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be fine.
坐下
Sit.
别走
Stay.
-乔  -太迟了
- Joe! - Too late.
我刚已经把你的肾在桑给巴尔的黑市上卖掉了
I just sold your kidney on the black market in Zanzibar.
乔  你哥哥想好好泡个澡呢
Joe, your brother's trying to take a bath.
要尊重隐私啊
Privacy, please.
妈  别啊
Mom, no.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道你是我们家的大诗人
I know that you're the poet in the family,
但我也给你写了点东西
but I wrote you a little something.
妈
Oh, Mom.
我才是幸运的那个
I'm the lucky one.
我会很想你的  但我很激动
I'm gonna miss you so much, but I am so excited
你要开始你自己的冒险旅程了
that you're going to have adventures on your own.
我会的
I will.
我也会非常想你的
And I'm gonna miss you, too.
要平安无恙地回来
Come back in one piece.
我保证
I promise.
你...  我这是该怎么逃出来
What... How am I supposed to get out?!
这里有所有你逃生需要用的一切
You have everything you need to figure it out.
降下你的心率  观察你的四周
Slow down your heartbeat, look at your surroundings.
-这房间  -是啊
- This room. - Yeah.
你还好吗
You okay?
不禁让我想起来
It just got me thinking
在我们最早刚搬进来时  那空荡荡的房子
about the empty house we first moved into.
新婚夫妇计划着横跨美国之旅
Couple of newlyweds planning a cross-country trip,
但我却不停孕吐
but I kept getting morning sickness.
你就搬了两个箱子  迪兰
You carried two boxes, Dylan.
而我搬[怀]过两个人类呢
I carried two humans.
当然是指茵素跟乔治啊  不然还能有谁
Yes, Poppy and George. Who else?
我们当时也挺快就上手了啊
We got the hang of it pretty fast.
是啊  我们一开始感觉自己挺行的一阵子  然后...
Yeah, we were feeling pretty smart for a while and...
大伙们  我正在跟日内瓦的房东通电话
Guys, I'm on the phone with the landlord in Geneva.
公寓有4.5乘11米大
The apartment he has is 4 1/2 by 11 meters.
我之后再给你答复
I'll have to get back to you.
没有  我只是在跟着一只苍蝇的轨迹
No, no, I was just following the path of this fly.
我答应了  对  给我几秒钟
Ugh! I'll do it. Okay, give me a second.
你们谁的手最稳
Which one of you has the steadiest hands?
卢克
Oh, Luke,
上次发生后  我们去弄了备份钥匙
we got a second key the last time that happened.
就放在厨房抽屉里  跟我过来
It's in the kitchen drawer. Come on.
所以基本上...  25年来无休止的疯狂
So, that's pretty much... 25 years of uninterrupted crazy.
突然一瞬间  它说结束就结束了
Then, when it ends... it ends.
直到我们开启人生新的篇章
Until our next chapter.
我现在只是随便想点主意  但...
I'm just brainstorming here, but, uh...
或许我们可以去延宕多年的横跨我国房车旅了
maybe we take a long-delayed RV trip across the United States,
并跟职棒大联盟每一队的吉祥物人偶合照
get selfies with all the Major League baseball mascots.
我肯定是超爱你  因为我觉得听起来好有意思啊
I must really love you, 'cause that sounds fun.
他们真的要离开了
They're really leaving.
我们该怎么做
What do we do?
跟所有父母一样
What people have always done.
为游子留一盏门廊灯
Leave the porch light on.
总有一天他们会回来
They come back.
各位
Everyone!
在我们叫的车来之前  我想说几句
I would like to, um, say a few words before our car comes.
其实就是两个简单的字  谢谢
Two simple words, actually... thank you...
让我有被欢迎进这个大家庭的感觉
...for making me feel so welcome in this family.
一个教会了我许多事物的家庭
A family that taught me so much.
从杰那里  我学会了直接点别废话
From Jay, I learned to get to the point.
小卡  我们就几分钟时间  能不能...
Cam, we only have a few minutes. Why don't...
我知道大多数人在这种时刻会多愁善感
I know people tend to get mushy in moments like this,
尽管你要去环游世界
but with you headed around the world
我要去上大学...
and me headed off to college...
我们会保持联系的
We'll stay close.
你为什么从来不写诗给我啊
How come you never wrote a poem for me?
你还不懂吗
Don't you get it?
所有的诗都是写给你的啊
They were all for you.
帽子[西语]
Sombrero.
你是...
What are you?
我知道你是阳性词[阳刚的]
I know you're masculine.
-你到底是出了什么问题  -你在说什么呢
- What is wrong with you? - What are you talking about?
你的举止很奇怪  快吓死我了
You're acting crazy, and it's scaring me.
你还很年轻  不应该像个老头子一样
You're too young to be acting like an old man.
这样我今年夏天
so I'll know what's going on
跟你去哥伦比亚时我才会知道都发生了什么
when I go with you to Colombia this summer.
你要来吗
You're coming?!
过去12年来你一直盯着我的家人看
You've been staring at my family for 12 years.
我为了你  去盯你家人一个夏天也很合理
Least I can do is stare at yours for one summer.
你真是太好了
You're wonderful.
但不许盯他们
But no staring,
也永远永远不许走同一条路线两次
and never, ever take the same route twice.
好啦  大伙们  都挤过来
Okay, everybody, squeeze in.
都挤过来拍照
Squeeze in for the picture.
好
Okay.
完美  我拍好了
Perfect. I got it!
好
Okay.
我都有点不想松手了
I kind of don't want to let go.
对啊  我也是
Yeah, me neither.
虽然现在是米奇舅舅与小卡要走  但...
I mean, it's Mitch and Cam now, but...
他们三个也马上要走了
it's these three next.
谁知道我们下次再相聚会是何时
Who knows when we'll all be together again.
为什么这么难啊
Why is this so hard?
这都是我们今天大概第7次要告别了
We've done this like seven times already today.
会这么难是因为我们之间的感情非同凡响
It's hard because not everybody gets to have what we have.
米奇尔  我把滑冰的奖杯放到你行李箱里了
Mitchell, I put the skating trophy in your suitcase.
我想先放你那边
I want you to have it first...
这样到时候你才会带回来给我
...so that I know you'll come back.
好吧  我来当个模范
Okay, um... I'm gonna set an example
第一个先放手
and be the first one to let go.
太难受了
It was awful.
人生变化如风云莫测
Life is full of change...
有时风大  有时雨小
some big, some small.
很久以前我就学会了  人可以逆风雨前行
I learned a long time ago, you can fight it...
也可以尝试迎风潇洒起舞
...or you can try to make the best of it.
如果有爱你的人在身旁  这一切会轻松许多
And that's all a lot easier if you've got people who love you...
人生再大的风风雨雨  也能笑脸相迎浑不怕
...helping you face whatever life throws at you.
至少这信念令我夜以成眠
At least, that's what helps me sleep at night.